<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>functional-programming on @juanitodread</title>
    <link>https://juanitodread.github.io/tags/functional-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in functional-programming on @juanitodread</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 20:52:38 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://juanitodread.github.io/tags/functional-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Functional data structures</title>
      <link>https://juanitodread.github.io/post/functional-data-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 20:52:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juanitodread.github.io/post/functional-data-structures/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction 1.1 What is a Functional Data Structure? 1.2 How does a Functional Data Structure work? 2. Linked list as a functional data structure 2.1 Factory method 2.2 Head 2.3 Tail 2.4 Adding elements (prepend) 2.5 Dropping elements 3. Conclusion 4. Code 4.1 FList implementation 4.2 FList unit test 1. Introduction Link to heading 1.1 What is a Functional Data Structure? Link to heading First, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the definition of Data Structure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymorphic functions in Scala</title>
      <link>https://juanitodread.github.io/post/polymorphic-functions-in-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 15:49:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juanitodread.github.io/post/polymorphic-functions-in-scala/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction 2. Functions 2.1 Monomorphic function 2.2 Polymorphic function 2.2.1 Verifying sorting in descendent order 2.2.2 Verifying sorting in a list of Double 2.2.3 Verifying sorting in a list of Boolean 2.2.4 Verifying sorting in a list of String 2.2.4.1 Verifying sorting based on string’s length 3. Conclusion 1. Introduction Link to heading A Polymorphic function is a very common term in Functional Programming.&#xA;In Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) also exists the concept of &amp;ldquo;Polymorphism&amp;rdquo; but it refers to objects and inheritance.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
