<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pattern Matching on @juanitodread</title>
    <link>https://juanitodread.github.io/tags/pattern-matching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pattern Matching on @juanitodread</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 20:52:38 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juanitodread.github.io/tags/pattern-matching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Functional data structures</title>
      <link>https://juanitodread.github.io/post/functional-data-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 20:52:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juanitodread.github.io/post/functional-data-structures/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction  1.1 What is a Functional Data Structure? 1.2 How does a Functional Data Structure work?   2. Linked list as a functional data structure  2.1 Factory method 2.2 Head 2.3 Tail 2.4 Adding elements (prepend) 2.5 Dropping elements   3. Conclusion 4. Code  4.1 FList implementation 4.2 FList unit test    1. Introduction 1.1 What is a Functional Data Structure? First, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the definition of Data Structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Builder pattern in Scala</title>
      <link>https://juanitodread.github.io/post/builder-pattern-in-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 23:47:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juanitodread.github.io/post/builder-pattern-in-scala/</guid>
      <description>The Builder Pattern is a design pattern for create objects. The builder pattern allows to the user the creation of an object that requires a lot of parameters in its constructor.
The problem with objects that requires different parameters to be constructed is that the programmer will need to overload the constructor to support all the distinct combinations of parameters.
In Java is very common to create a new class (the builder) object that will receives all the parameters and builds a new object with the parameters received.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
